Guide to the James Montgomery Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Montgomery collection
1789-1920
1803-1850
GEN MSS 878
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.96
(3 boxes)
The collection contains letters from James Montgomery to various friends, colleagues, and associates, including authors, publishers, and clergymen; recipients include John Aikin, Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Robert Hartley Davenport, George Williams Fulcher, Thomas Raffles, and Robert Southey. Much of the content relates to Montgomery's writings and publications, in particular his poetry and work for hymnals, though some of the letters are personal in nature. Also present is a small group of autograph manuscript poems and other writings by Montgomery, including two poems translated into Welsh. Reference material in the collection includes clippings about Montgomery, portrait engravings, and material pertaining to his life, death, and funeral proceedings, including a copy of The Death of James Montgomery, Esq. with a Sketch of his Life (1854).
Montgomery, James, 1771-1854
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased as a collection from Maggs Bros. Ltd. on the Plain Fund, 1954. Five additions acquired by gift and purchase from various sources are noted at the folder level in the Collection Contents list.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The James Montgomery Collection primarily contains letters written by him to various friends, colleagues, and professional associates, as well as a group of his writings, and a selection of historical and reference material related to his life and death.
Series I holds letters to Montgomery's friends, fellow authors, his publishers, and various clergymen. Recipients include Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Barbara Hofland, and Hannah More, among many others. Multiple letters exist for several of his correspondents, including more than twenty sent to the author and editor (and medical doctor) John Aikin in London; these letters are the longest and most descriptive in the collection, with seven written on oversize sheets of paper. Other multiple letter sets are present for Robert Hartley Davenport (6), George Williams Fulcher (6), John Holland (5), Thomas Raffles (11), Robert Southey (4), and Miss Thompson (8). Most letters have the recipients' postal addresses as part of their document. Much of the content relates to Montgomery's writings and publications, in particular his poetry and work for hymnals, though some of the letters are personal in nature.
Series II holds a group of autograph manuscript poems and other writings by Montgomery, including two poems translated into Welsh. Series III holds clippings about Montgomery, portrait engravings, and material pertaining to his death and funeral proceedings, including a copy of The Death of James Montgomery, Esq. with a Sketch of his Life (1854).
James Montgomery (1771-1854)
James Montgomery was an English author, editor, and resident of Sheffield, England.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Letters from James Montgomery, 1789-1853. II. Writings of James Montgomery, 1821-1852. III. Other Papers, 1824-1920.
Authors, English -- 19th century -- Archives; English literature -- 19th century; Poets, English -- 19th century; Engravings (prints); Memorials (Commemorative) -- England -- Sheffield -- 1854; Authors, English -- 19th century; Poets, English -- 19th century; Portrait prints; Aikin, John, 1747-1822; Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834; Cromek, R. H. (Robert Hartley), 1770-1812; Davenport, R. A. (Richard Alfred), 1777?-1852; Fulcher, G. W. (George Williams), 1795-1855; Gardiner, William, 1770-1853; Hofland, Mrs. (Barbara), 1770-1844; McIlvaine, Charles Pettit, 1799-1873; Montgomery, James, 1771-1854; Montgomery, James, 1771-1854 -- Portraits; More, Hannah, 1745-1833; Raffles, Thomas, 1788-1863; Southey, Robert, 1774-1843
- Letters from James Montgomery, 1789-1853; Series I; 129
  Arrangement
  Arranged in alphabetical order by recipient, followed by sixteen letters to unidentified recipients filed chronologically at the end.
  - Aikin, John, of Stoke Newington, 1803 Sep 23
    Scope and Contents
    Autograph letter; a long letter to Dr. Aikin; Montgomery apologizes for not having replied previously, and deals with various matters, such as his school, his childhood, remarks on poetry, etc.
  - Aikin, John, 1806 Apr 15
    Autograph letter; Montgomery mentions a poem he had hoped to enclose, his publishers Longman & Co., and a second edition of his works.
  - Aikin, John, 1806 Jul 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks Dr. Aikin for superintending the second edition of his poems.
  - Aikin, John, 1806 Jul 30
    Autograph letter, signed; with regard to Montgomery's poems.
  - Aikin, John, 1806 Oct 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Autograph letter, signed; dealing with some poems; Montgomery makes a few corrections and alterations in the wording.
  - Aikin, John, 1806 Nov 12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks Dr. Aikin for superintending the third edition of his poems.
  - Aikin, John, of Stoke Newington, 1807 Jan 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery refers to the publishers of the "Monthly Mirror"; Mr. Rhodes wishes to insert a memoir and portrait of Montgomery in this journal.
  - Aikin, John, 1807 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery discusses a critique of his poems that appeared in the Edinburgh Review.
  - Aikin, John, 1807 Aug 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Autograph letter, signed; in this letter Montgomery recalls the time when he was associated with Campbell & Grahame.
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1807 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Autograph letter, signed; written from Sheffield.
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1807 Dec 31
    Autograph letter; enclosing Part III of the poem, "The West Indies."
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1808 Mar 9
    Autograph letter; a long letter, together with the fourth part of the poem "The West Indies."
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1808 Aug 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Autograph letter; the letter is relative to a sketch of the history of Montgomery's mind, which Dr. Aikin has asked him to furnish.
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1808 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery has made the personal acquaintance of Dr. Aikin, and thanks him for his kindness during a visit.
  - Aikin, John, of London, 1809 Mar 11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Autograph letter; this letter, among other things, deals with a ship lost in a storm, and Montgomery has included a poem, "The Castaway Ship."
  - Aikin, John, 1809 Jul 15
    Autograph letter, signed; enclosing original manuscript of Canto I of The World Before the Flood.
  - Aikin, John, 1809 Oct 9
    Autograph letter, signed; enclosing original manuscript of Canto II of The World Before the Flood.
  - Aikin, John, 1810 Jan 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery enquires about Dr. Aikin's health. He also mentions "The West Indies."
  - Aikin, John, of Stoke Newington, 1811 Jul 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery deals with certain poems, etc., in this letter.
  - Aikin, John, of Stoke Newington, 1812 Apr 21 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Autograph letter, signed; a personal letter, in which he mentions Miss Aikin's visit to Edinburgh, etc.
  - Aikin, John, of Stoke Newington, 1812 Sep 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Autograph letter, signed; written on a folder containing a poem, "The Peak Mountains" by "J. M." in two parts.
  - Ball, Mr., of Sheffield, 1837 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Autograph letter, signed; concerning the choice of a motto for Mr. Ball.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift, 1957.
  - Barker, Edward, 1832 Jun 29 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery states he has not found it convenient to engage himself upon any committee in behalf of gentleman offering themselves as candidates for Parliament, but he mentions the name of his friend Samuel Bailey.
  - Blackwell, John, of Newcastle, 1838 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery conveys his respects to Mr. and Mrs. Blackwell.
  - Boyd, Joseph B., of Cincinnati, Ohio, 1838 Sep 22 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding a certain poem (no title given).
  - Brady, Henry, of Dublin, 1827 Nov 15 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Autograph letter; mentions Montgomery's poem, "Greenland."
  - Braneld, Mr., 1789 Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Autograph letter; written to a bookseller when Montgomery was 18, and he offers some poems for publication.
  - Carder, Josiah, of London, 1809 Oct 6 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery tells Mr. Carder he has been much indisposed since his return from Scarborough, and deals with a certain poem.
  - Chantrey, Francis Legatt, of Pimlico, London, 1820 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Autograph letter, signed; this letter was written by Montgomery to serve as an introduction for his friend, Rowland Hodgson, to Mr. Chantrey.
  - Christy, Joseph, of Stockport, 1835 Apr 21 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Montgomery's "Hymn for Children." He tells Mr. Christy he can make use of it as he likes.
  - Cochrane & Pickersgill, of Waterloo Place, 1831 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery also encloses an original manuscript, "Lord Falkland's Dream."
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, of Grasmere, Kendal, 1808 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery informs Mr. Coleridge he has been able to obtain two subscribers to Mr. Coleridge's intended work.
  - Cottle, Joseph, of Brunswick Square, 1819 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks his friend for his offer of help and financial assistance.
  - Cromek, Robert Hartley, of London, 1810 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Autograph letter, signed; referring to a volume Mr. Cromek has sent Montgomery.
  - Davenport, Richard Alfred, of London, 1802-1814 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Six autograph letters and autograph letters, signed; Montgomery writes in regard to The Poetical Register, and various poems he submits for publication.
  - Doncaster, Mrs., of Sheffield, 1828 Nov 27 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery conveys his respects and wonders if "she will have an early opportunity of enclosing a small parcel of Missionary Reports to Miss Rowntree of York."
  - Everett, James, 1836 Feb 26 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery mentions Miss Gales' failing health in this letter.
  - Everett, James, [1844] (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery states he cannot be present at York owing to having received a letter from his sister announcing the serious illness of her son, and asking him to visit them at Bedford.
  - Fairbanks, William, 1835 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Autograph letter, signed; this letter is with regard to the Peckham Negro Friends Society and a school for adult Negroes in Jamaica
  - Fincher, Joseph, of Albemarle St., 1832 Apr 11 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Autograph letter, signed; this is with regard to some business with Cochrane & Co., and mentions Longman & Co.
  - Fincher, Joseph, of London, 1832 Jun 20 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding a sum of £10. Montgomery also refers to a course of lectures he has been asked to deliver.
  - Fincher, Joseph, of London, 1842 Aug 4 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery mentions the passing of a dear friend, Mr. George Bennet.
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1833 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks Mr. Fulcher for the "elegant little books." He also appends an autographed poem.
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1840 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding some verses which Montgomery transmitted for Mr. Fulcher's "Annual."
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1841 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery acknowledges £1.1.0. for a fund opened for the missionaries in Greenland.
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1842 Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery acknowledges two letters from Mr. Fulcher.
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1842 Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery acknowledges a donation of £2.2.0. and also sends a short poem, "The Dying Child's Request."
  - Fulcher, George Williams, of Sudbury, 1847 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery asks that his name be added to the list of subscribers of Fulcher's "lady editor of a volume of poem to be published in aid of the suffering sick."
  - Gardiner, William, of Leicester, 1807 Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery states in this letter that as a boy he wrote a great many hymns.
  - Gardiner, William, of Leicester, 1808 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Autograph letter, signed; together with hymn, "Father of Eternal Grace: Glorify Thyself in Me." Also an air, "Song of the Negro's Daughter."
  - Gardiner, William, of Leicester, 1808 Feb 24 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery thanks him for the air he has adapted to his hymn. He also sets out a poem, "A Midnight Thought," and "Song of the Negro's Daughter."
  - Hadfield, Samuel and George, 1836 Jul 4 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Autograph letter; enclosing poem, "The Dead Canary Bird." Accompanied by an engraved portrait of Montgomery.
  - Hare, Alice, 1829 Aug 12 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery has to decline Mrs. Hare's request for some verses.
  - Hayward, Sarah J., of Stroud, 1843 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Autograph letter, signed; enclosing poem, "Children's Pennies, and apologizing for not having forwarded the poem before. Accompanied by a note regarding the poem by Sarah Hayward.
  - Heaton, Mr., of Leeds, 1827 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Elizabeth Cooper's The Muses' Library.
  - Heppenstall, P., of Sheffield, 1834 Mar 6 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Autograph letter, signed; this is a letter of thanks for a gift.
  - Hofland, Barbara, 1835 Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding the return of an album to her. Accompanied by engraved portrait of Montgomery.
    Gift of James Hosmer Penniman, 1921; formerly part of the Penniman Memorial Library, Yale University.
  - Holland, John, 1827 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Autograph letter, signed; with regard to certain poems by Mr. Roberts which appeared in the Sheffield newspapers.
  - Holland, John, 1833 Mar 29 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Holland, John, 1833 Dec 21 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Autograph letter, signed; this deals with two manuscripts Mr. Holland has in hand.
  - Holland, John, 1838 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Autograph letter, signed; the letter announces the death of Anne.
  - Holland, John, 1841 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Autograph letter, signed; this letter is with regard to some matters appertaining to the museum.
  - Howitt, Richard, of Nottingham, 1830 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Autograph letter, signed; a letter of thanks for a volume of poems which Mr. Howitt sent Montgomery.
  - Hudson, J. W., of Leeds, 1847 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery has been asked to attend a meeting of the Leeds Mechanic's Institute and Library.
  - [Hunter, Joseph?], 1835 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding some stones sent to Montgomery. Written from 10, New Palace Yard, [London?].
  - Hunter, Joseph, of London, 1839 Jan 16 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding the Gas Light Company's affairs.
  - Hunter, Joseph, 1840 Mar 5 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Autograph letter, signed; with regard to the Gas Light Company dividend, etc.
  - Hunter, Joseph, of London, 1844 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding the Reverend Hunter's son, who has made application as a candidate for the place of assistant to the House Surgeon of the Infirmary.
  - Hunter, Henry J., of Sheffield, 1848 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Autograph letter, signed; this is with regard to Election Day. Written from Fulneck, near Leeds.
  - Jervis, Swynfen, of London, 1843 Jan 25 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding the lectures on poetry and general literature which Montgomery states he gave some years ago at the Royal Institution.
  - Leader, Robert, 1848 Oct 11 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Autograph letter, signed; this refers to a lecture given by Montgomery at the Royal Institute in London.
  - Livett, James, of Bristol, 1822 Mar 12 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery encloses a copy of the rules of the Mechanic's Library, and also mentions a Reading and Conversation Society.
  - Longman & Co., 1803 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding the return of proof sheets of a work by Montgomery.
  - Longman & Co., of London, 1828 Feb 2 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery asks for a complete copy of his poems, and also a copy of the The Christian Psalmist and The Christian Poet to be sent to Miss Farrer of London.
  - [Longman & Co.?], 1844 Apr 4 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery requests that certain books are sent to him.
  - McIlvaine, Charles Pettit, of Ohio, 1833 Dec 4 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery mentions in this letter a certain Mr. West, also Bishop Chase, and Kenyon College, Ohio.
  - Manners, G., of Dewsbury, 1841 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery criticizes some poems by Mr. Manners.
  - Marples, D., of Liverpool, 1844 Aug 12 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding six lectures on poets which Montgomery is engaged to deliver at the Collegiate Institution at Liverpool.
  - Montagu, Mrs. Basil, of Lincoln's Inn, 1811 Jul 16 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    Autograph letter, signed; a long letter touching on various points, such as Mr. Montagu being called to the Chancery Bar.
  - Montgomery, Robert, of Woolwich, 1837 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    Autograph letter, signed; a letter of farewell to his brother. Written from Hackney.
  - More, Hannah, of Barley Woods, 1824 Feb 27 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Autograph letter; acknowledging receipt of certain sums of money for the fund on behalf of Mrs. Caterall and her children.
  - Moxon, Edward, of Dover Street, London, 1833 Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks Mr. Moxon for a token sent him.
  - Piper, H. H., of Norton, 1826 Jan 14 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Montgomery's upcoming appearance in Norton.
  - Preston, M. M., 1824 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery requests his patronage for the Library for Mechanics and Apprentices of Sheffield.
    Purchase, 1956.
  - Pringle, Thomas, of London, 1830 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Autograph letter, signed; with regard to a Mr. Brayham offering himself as candidate for Parliament. Montgomery says some words in his praise.
  - Raffles, Thomas, of Liverpool, 1807-1844 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    Autograph letters, signed; eleven letters written from Sheffield between March 29, 1807 and September 10, 1844.
  - Rathbone, Hannah Mary, of Liverpool, 1852 Jul 12 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Autograph letter; dealing with a volume containing "Memoirs of Richard Reynolds."
  - Rawling, C. George, of Liverpool, 1842 Mar 24 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    Autograph letter, signed; to the secretary of the Antimonopoly Association of Liverpool, dealing with an invitation to the Great Free Trade Demonstration there.
  - Ray, Mr., of Sheffield, 1819 Oct 21 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Mr. Carlisle, a London bookseller, who is being convicted for selling blasphemous publications.
  - Reece, Miss, of Sheffield, 1833 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    Autograph letter, signed; Miss Reece has evidently asked Montgomery for some poems, and he replies "...if anything fit to send you comes into my mind, I shall be happy to please your correspondent and yourself."
  - Reece, Miss, of Sheffield, 1833 Oct 11 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery encloses the "long delayed" stanza "The Negro is Free."
  - Rodgers, Paul, of Sheffield, 1840 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    Autograph letter; regarding a poem written by Montgomery.
  - Rodgers, Paul, of Sheffield, 1846 Jan 17 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery criticizes some of Mr. Rodgers' verses.
  - Roscoe, William, of Allerton Hall, 1815 Oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    Autograph letter; a letter of thanks to Mr. and Mrs. Roscoe.
  - Ryder, Richard, of Whitehall, London, 1811 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    Autograph letter, signed; this letter deals with the affairs of the British Linen Co., and as Deputy Governor, Montgomery "begs leave to present a Memorial upon the same subject." On the reverse side is Mr. Ryder's reply, dated April 29, 1811.
  - Shoberl, Frederic, of London, 1832 Oct 19 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Montgomery's poem, "The Skylark."
  - Smith, Miss, of The Mount, Sheffield, 1837 Nov 15 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery sends two volumes to Miss Smith, with his best respects.
  - Southey, Robert, 1812 Sep 18 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    Autograph letter; written on a printed folder containing Montgomery's poem "The Peak Mountains." He mentions Southey's "Pilgrim's Progress."
  - Southey, Robert, of Keswick, 1815 Mar 27 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery states he has been seriously ill. He mentions "Roderick, the Last of the Goths."
  - Southey, Robert, of Keswick, 1829 Apr 24 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    Autograph letter; this letter deals with a memoir that Southey is writing of John Bunyan.
  - Southey, Robert, of Keswick, 1829 Jun 23 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery apologizes for not having had an opportunity of visiting him, as he had been visiting various towns on the "occasion of the anniversaries of their respective Bible Societies..."
  - Taylor and Hessey, of London, 1816 Mar 23 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    Autograph letter, signed; enquiring the terms for publishing a story.
  - Taylor and Hessey, of London, 1816 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    Autograph letter, signed; this letter deals with The Blind Man and his Son.
  - Taylor and Hessey, of London, 1817 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding Mr. Sterndale the bearer of this letter. Montgomery speaks on his behalf.
  - Thompson, Miss, of Sheffield, 1807 Dec 2 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Autograph letter, signed; written from Hartshead.
  - Thompson, Miss H., of Fargate, Sheffield, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery thanks Miss Thompson for her kind note, and refers to some verses by Byron.
  - Thompson, Miss H., 1821 Feb 17 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    Autograph letter, signed; announcing the death of Miss Elizabeth Gales.
  - Thompson, Miss, 1822 Jan 10 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    Autograph letter; Montgomery sends his respects to Miss Thompson, and mentions a certain hymn book.
  - Thompson, Miss, 1822 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    Autograph letter, signed; Montgomery sends six copies of his Polyhymnia, or Select Airs by Celebrated Foreign Composers.
  - Thompson, Miss, 1827 Feb 14 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    Autograph letter, signed; regarding what he's reading.
  - Thompson, Miss, 1837 Nov 21 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    Autograph letter, signed.
  - Thompson, Miss, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    Autograph letter; a reply to an invitation to tea. Montgomery has to refuse. Written from Hartshead.
  - Tilt and Bogue, of London, 1841 Jun 10 (Box 2, Folder 106)